Guide to the Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics, 1970s-1990s LATINAMER.2015.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Latin American Countries, I.
  - Mexico, 8.
    - Santiago Levy, Mexico: Recent Economic Developments and Future Prospects (Talk prepared for the 1987 Alfred J. Hanna Distinguished Lecture Series on Mexico, Rollins College, Florida), November 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Levy, Daniel, and Gabriel Szekely. A Brief Political History in Stability and Mexico: Panorama of Change, pp. 21-47 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ely-Yamin, Alicia. Six Months After the U.N. Verdict: An Update on Impunity in the Mexican Federal Judicial Police. A North America Project Special Report. New York: World Policy Institute, April 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Huerta, David. Mexico and the United States: Relations on the Edge. Bucknell University, Lewisburg, Pennsylvania, May 8, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - De la Garza, Luis Santos. Ineffective Suffrage: The Denial of Political Rights in Mexico A North America Project Special Report. New York: World Policy Institute, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Roett, Riordan. Mexico's Strategic Alternatives in the Changing World System: Four Options, Four Ironies (not dated, chapter from book) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Silva-Herzog F., Jesus. Mexico and the World: Opportunities and Risks in the 1990s (not dated, chapter from book) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - La Mujer Obrera newsletter Chiapas dice Basta! (Includes Declaration of the Zapatista Army, Social and Economic Conditions in Chiapas, A Month of the Rebellion, Better to die fighting than to die of dysentery - an interview with Sub-Commandant Marcos of the EZLN, Announcement From the Leadership of the EZLN, Interview with Zapatista Mayor Mario - We want to be human beings, A Bishop (Samuel Ruiz) in the midst of conflict, and Revolutionary Laws Regarding Women), February 17, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Stahler-Sholk, Richard & Barbara (Claremont, California) Letter in support of the Zapatistas and appeal for (1) international peace observers, (2) financial and material aid, January 12, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - La Mujer Obrera. The Danger of a Civil War, if there is no Democracy: Marcos, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - National Coordinator of Civic Action for National Liberation Newsletter - Ya basta! (Includes editorial Nobody Surrenders! The EZLN says No! to the government, other articles - The Fear Campaign, Letter from the Clandestine Revolutionary Indigenous Committee and the EZLN, and Second Declaration for the Lacandona Jungle) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - National Coordinator of Civic Action for National Liberation (CONAC-LC) Newsletter - Describes CONAC-LC - legal representative of the EZLN. Describes EZLN demands (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - La Mujer Obrera. Letter from La Mujer Obrera seeking support for the EZLN, May 18, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - EZLN. Zapatista announcement of the Convocation of the Convention National Democratica for the 6-9 August, 1994. Gives purpose and demands of convention, July 9,1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Benson, Robert W. War Talk in Mexico, July 4, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - HONOR, Inc. Chiapas '94, A New Day Dawns, pamphlet put together after March '94, includes newspaper articles and communiques from the EZLN during January, February, and March of 1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Collection of introductory and more advanced articles about Zapatista uprising, April 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Kampwirth, Karen. From Feminine Guerrillas to Feminist Revolutionaries: Nicaragua, El Salvador, Chiapas. prepared for the 1997 LASA Conference, April 17-19, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Nicaragua, 9.
    - James Wittebols, The Politics and Coverage of Terrorism: From Media Images to Public Consciousness, August 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Paul Chambers, Ethnic Identity and National Revolution—Nicaragua's Atlantic Coast Under the Sandinistas (Poli/Sci 535 Fall/92. Student Paper), March 12, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Roger N. Lancaster, Skin Color, Race, and Racism in Nicaragua, Ethnology 34 (4) Oct. 1991: 339-53, October 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Roger N. Lancaster, Subject Honor and Object Shame: The Construction of Male Homosexuality and Stigma in Nicaragua. Ethnology 27(2) Apr. 1988: 111-25, April 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Philip A. Dennis, Herbal Medicine among the Miskito of Eastern Nicaragua Economic Botany 42(1) 1988: 16-28 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - The Ad Hoc Coalition of United States Sister Cities for Election Observation in Nicaragua, Mi Voto es Secreto, March 12, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Wolf Kramer-Mandeau, History of Sports in Nicaragua Before and After the Revolution (unpublished paper), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - John Kirk, Reflections on Rerum Novarum and the Catholic Church in Nicaragua (Student paper) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Michael Dodson, Religious Fundamentalism in Central America: General Reflections and a Nicaraguan Case Study (Paper presented to the XVI LASA Congress), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Ricard Gona, Domestic Political Actors Change in a new Political Environment: the Guatemalan and Nicaraguan Cases Compared (Paper presented to the XVI LASA congress), April 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - De Ann Pendry, The Misa Campesina: Revolutionary Change a la Nica (Presented to the XVI LASA Congress), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Wolf Kramer-Mandeau, Nicht als Zuschauer teilhaben, sondern als Protagonisten. Sport in Nicaragua nach 1979 (unpublished paper-German) (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Ocupacion, Dominacion y Liberacion - La Historia del Deporte en Nicaragua in Geschichte der Leibesubungen, Band 6 Berlin, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Jon Jonakin, Agro-Export Labor Shortage: An Estimation of the Impact of Technology Changes on Labor Demand in Nicaragua's Coffee Sector (unpublished paper), March 1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Shelley McConnell, Search for Elite Consensus: Political Concertation on the Nicaraguan Electoral System (Presented to the XVI LASA Congress), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Ricardo Chavarria, Estado y Sociedad en Nicaragua Centro Nicaraguense de Derechos Humanos, May 24, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Electoral Law and Reforms Supreme Electoral Council, Republic of Nicaragua (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - John Foran and Jeff Goodwin, Revolutionary Outcomes in Iran and Nicaragua: Coalition Fragmentation, War, and the Limits fo Social Transformation (Paper prepared for delivery at the Annual Meeting of the American Sociological Association 1991), August 23-27, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Veronica Rojas, Resultados Electorales y Participacion de la Mujer Octubre, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Vanessa Castro, Resultados Electorales en el Sector Rural, Instituto para el Desarrollo de la Democracia, Managua, October 1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Consejo Supremo Electoral. Elecciones 1990 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Jack Spence, Will Everything be Better? ('Close to Final Draft' of paper to be published in Comment), July 17, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Robert Sahr, U.S. Media Framing of the 1990 Nicaraguan Elections (Paper for presentation at the Meetings of the Political Communication Research Group, Bled, Yugoslavia), August 26-31, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Stephen Kent and Anne Cooper, The 1984 and 1990 Nicaraguan Elections: Newsmagazine Coverage Vs. Neutral Observers' Reports, June 24-29, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Carlos M. Vilas, Contribucion de la Politica Economica y la Negociacion Internacional a la Caida del Gobierno Sandinista (unpublished paper) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Daniel Ortega, selected speeches (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Polling Failure in Nicaragua Assessed, Interamerican Public Opinion Report, Survey Research in Latin America and the Caribbean, Spring 1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Elections and Democratization in Nicaragua (draft of paper to be published in the Journal of Inter American Studies and World Affairs), July 11, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Dennis Gilbert, The Vanguard and Democracy in Sandinista Thought (prepared for meetings of the Canadian Association of Latin American and Caribbean Studies, Ottawa, Canada, 1989), October 5-7, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Assorted Materials from the 1990 Nicaraguan Elections (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Nicaragua Election Monitor WOLA, N.5, January 4, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Fred Turner, Our Work on the Nicaraguan Elections, March 5, 1990 (Memorandum sent to William Bollinger and the other members of the Commission on Preelection Polls) (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Election Nicaragua 1990, Update N. 3 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Election Nicaragua 1990, Update N. 4 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Gordon Bowen, Presidential Action and Public Opinion about U.S. Nicaraguan Policy: Limits to the Rally 'Round the Flag' Syndrome, Political Science and Politics Dec, 1989 Vol. XXII, December 6, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Carter, Evans and Oduber to Observe Campaign in Nicaragua; Carter Announces Entire Delegation, Including Congressmen, News from the Carter Center, November 1989 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Comparisons of Electoral Laws in: Chile, Costa Rica, Guatemala, Nicaragua, Paraguay and Venezuela, May 1989 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - U.S. Assistance to Nicaraguan Guerrillas: Issues for the Congress CRS Issue Brief, March 1988 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Nicaragua: Conditions and Issues for US Policy, Congressional Research Service (CRS) Issue Brief, July 7, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Congressional Research Service, the Library of Congress, Various articles about Nicaragua (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Nicaragua; National and Regional Accords Benefit Elections, Washington Office of Latin America, Update, Jul-Aug 1989, Vol XIV, July/August 1989 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Mark Everingham, Economic Development under Dictatorship and Revolutionary Coalitions: the Case of Nicaragua (Presented at the XV LASA Congress), December 1989 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Amnesty International. The Human Rights Record 1986-1989: Update, October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Bill Barnes, Public Opinion Polling in Nicaragua (draft paper), July 30, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Humberto Belli, Voting Time in Nicaragua, Election Nearing, The New Republic, 1989: 16-19, November 1989 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Nicaraguan Election Update #2, Foreign Funding of the Internal Opposition, Hemisphere Initiatives, October 16, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Lobo, Jose. Lance Taylor interview, September 1989 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Political Agreement (Unofficial translation) Envio p.40-42, September 1989 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Bilateral Accord Between Nicaragua and Honduras (Unofficial translation). Envio p.45 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - William A. Barnes, Hegemony, Opposition and Democratization in the Nicaraguan Revolution (unpublished paper), August 1998 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Christopher Neal and Barbara Stewart, Nicaragua Election Handbook, a Guide for Canadian Journalists covering the 1990 Nicaraguan Elections, Published by the Committee for Peace and Democracy in Nicaragua, October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Intervention Vs. Self-Determination: the U.S. and Canada in Nicaragua's 1990 Elections, Central America Update (special supplement), September/October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Carlos Tunnermann Bemheim, La Educacion de Nicaragua Antes, Durante y Despues de la Revolucion Popular Sandinista (Unpublished paper-Califomia State U, Sacramento) (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Richard Stahler-Sholk, Labor/Party/State Dynamics in Nicaragua: Union Responses to Austerity Under the Sandinista and UNO Governments, (Paper presented to the XVII International Congress of LASA), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Mathew Conrad, The Triumph of the Letrado: Nicaraguan Political Poetry as Political Ideology (Student paper for Latin American Political Thought, Spring/91), Spring 1991 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Wolf Kramer-Mandeau, European Festival and Games Culture of the Middle Ages and the Early Modern Times and its Encounter with Latin American Cultures during the Conquista, Sportliche Festkultur in Geschichtlicher Perspektive, 1990: 137-177 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Jon Jonakin, External Interference and Work Incentives on Agricultural Production Cooperatives in Nicaragua (Unpublished paper, Tennessee Technological U.) (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Worker Self-Management and Work Incentives on Nicaraguan Agricultural Production Cooperatives: an Investigation of Relative Performance (Unpublished paper, Tennessee Technological U.) (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Peter Utting, The Peasant Question and Development Policy in Nicaragua, UNRISD (United Nations Research Institute for Social Development), February 1998 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 15 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 16 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 17 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 18 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 19 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 20 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 21 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 22 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Pre-Election Polls Docs. 24 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - William Barnes, Rereading the Nicaraguan Pre-Election Polls in the Light of the Election Results (Unpublished paper, draft), December 30, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Kenneth Mijeski, Women and the FSLN: A Multivariate Analysis of the Female Vote in the 1990 Nicaraguan Elections (Paper for delivery at the 1992 Annual meeting of the Southeast Council of Latin American Studies), April 1992 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Philip Williams, Ten Years of Revolution: The Nicaraguan Church (Presented to the XV LAS A Congress, Sn. Juan, Puerto Rico), September 21-23, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Commission on Nicaragua Preelection Polls, Update on the Commission's Process, February 6, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Nicaraguan Election Issues. Violence is an Issue--But Whose Violence? Central American Historical Institute, Georgetown University, Issue 8, February 10, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Nicaraguan Election Issues. The Level Playing Field Argument. Central American Historical Institute, Georgetown University Issues 9, February 12, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - William Bollinger, Pollsters Invade Nicaragua Interamerican Public Opinion Report Survey Research in latin America and the Caribbean, January 1990 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Carlos M. Vila, Especulaciones Sobre Una Sorpresa: Las Elecciones en Nicaragua, Desarrollo Economico Revista de Ciencias Sociales Vol. 30 (118), July/September 1990 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Carter, Council Monitor Nicaraguan Elections, Peaceful Transition of Power First in Country's History, The Carter Center News, Spring 1990 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Nicaraguan Election Update #2 Foreign Funding of the Internal Opposition Hemisphere Initiatives, October 16, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Michael Zalkin, Rural Workers or 'Peasants'? Agrarian Class Structure in Nicaragua (Paper presented to the XV LASA Congress, San Juan, Puerto Rico), September 21-23, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Johannes P. Van Gut, Democratic Organization for Social Transformation: A Comparative Case Study of Nicaragua's Christian Base Communities in the Revolutionary Process (unpublished paper, Loyola University of Chicago) (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Eric Selbin, The Consolidation of Social Revolutions: Societal Transformation in the Nicaraguan Revolution (Paper for delivery at the XV LASA Congress, 1989) (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Luis Serra, Participacion Campesina en el Movimiento Cooperativo Nicaraguense (Ponencia al XV Congreso de LASA), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Max Spoor, Reforma Economica y Credito Rural en Nicaragua (1988-89) (Paper presented to the XV LASA Congress), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Contra Campaign Violence Nicaragua Hotline, August 25, 1989-January 24, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Primer Congreso del Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional Carlos Nunez Tellez Informe Central de la Direccion National del FSLN, Managua, July 19, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Clare M. Weber, Peace Making and Reconciliation at the Grassroots: A Case Study of the Peace Commissions of Nueva Guinea, Nicaragua, 1987-1992 (Paper for presentation to the XVII LASA congress, Los Angeles, California) (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - B.H. Harlow, The Nicaraguan-Contra Peace Negotiations of 1988 (Unpublished paper, U. of Regina) (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - The 1990 Elections or How Capitalism and Western Democracy Stopped the Revolution (Paper for presentation at the 1992 LASA congress, Los Angeles) (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Tim Bossenbroek, The Sandinistas, the Miskitos and the United States: the US Manipulation of the Sandinista/Miskito Conflict (Unpublished Paper), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - National Endowment for Democracy Accused of Grossly Violating Charter in Nicaraguan Election Witness for Peace (News Release), February 5, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Daniel Estrada Nicaragua's Worker-Peasant Alliance: A Case Study of Economic Democracy and the Gamez-Garmendia, 1979 to 1989 (Paper prepared for the XV LASA Congress) (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Daniel Wolf, The Institutionalization of Competitive Politics in Nicaragua (presented to the XV LASA Congress), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Guns for Drugs? Senate Probers Trace an old Contra Connection to George Bush's Office Newsweek, May 23, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.1, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.2, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.3, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.4, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.5, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.6, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.7, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.8, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.9, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.10, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents No.11, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.12, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Commissions on Nicaragua Preelection Polls Commission Documents no.13, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Consejo Supremo Electoral. Boletin Informativo, October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Anne Cooper and Stephen O'Brien, Newsmagazine Coverage of the 1984 and 1990 Nicaraguan Elections (Ohio U Paper-Submitted to the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication Annual Convention, 1990), August 9-12, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Luis Serra, Desarrollo Agropecuario y Participacion Politica del Campesinado Durante el Somocismo (Copy of manuscript-Unpublished book) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - David Close, Responding to Low Intensity Conflict: Counterinsurgency in Nicaragua (Presented to the XV LASA Congress, San Juan, Puerto Rico), September 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Patricia Edmisten, The Political Writings of Pedro Chamorro Cardenal (Presented to the XV LASA Congress, San Juan, Puerto Rico), September 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Gives Contras Ultimatum on Aid New York Times 1990: A10, March 20, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letter from Managua The New Yorker, March 26, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Joan Font y Ricard Goma, El Proceso de Democratizacion en Nicaragua, Actores, Estrategias y Conflicto (Universita de Barcelona-Presentado en el III Encuentro Debate America Latina Ayer y Hoy) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Joan Font and Joaquim Molins, The February 1990 Election in Nicaragua: A Democratic consolidation Process? (Paper presented for the workshop on Prospects and Dilemmas of Democratic Consolidation in Latin America, ECPR Joint Sessions, Bochum), April 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Jeff Morris, The Influence of United States Economic and Military Aggression on Agrarian Reform in Sandinista Nicaragua (Student Paper, Ohio University) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Julia Preston, The Defeat of the Sandinistas The New York Review of Books 25-29 (Original newspaper article and photocopy), April 12, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Paul Oquist, Dinamica Socio-Politica de las Elecciones Nicaraguenses 1990, Analisis de los Resultados Globales Instituto de Estudios Nicaraguenses, Managua, October 27, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Robert Pastor, Nicaragua's Choice, The Making of a Free Election Journal of Democracy, Vol 1 (3), Summer 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Jacqueline Sharkey, How U.S. Money Affected the Outcome in Nicaragua, Anatomy of an Election, Common Cause Magazine, May/June 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Alexander Cockburn, The Invasion of Nicaragua The Nation, May 7, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - MALAS Forum, March 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - MALAS Forum, May 1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Steve Ropp, Military Retrenchment and Decay in Panama Washington Post, April 23, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Republica de Nicaragua, Nicaragua: Program for Economic Recovery and Growth 1991-1994 (Statement Presented by the Government of Nicaragua at the Meeting of the Consultative Group of Donor Countries in Washington, D.C.), March 25, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Union Nacional de Agricultores y Ganaderos (UNAG), Productores, May 1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Union Nacional de Agricultores y Ganaderos (UNAG) Productores, April 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Union Nacional de Agricultores, Productores, March 1991 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - La Izquierda Latinoamericana, La Avispa Bimensualde Teoria y Debate, N.4 Managua, Nicaragua, April/May 1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Informe Sobre la Situacion Organizativa de la Asociacion de Trabjadores del Campo (Nicaragua) ATC (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Maria Veronica Frenkel, Food and Agricultural Policies in Nicaragua: Evolution of Policies under an Economic Crisis and the Contra War (Paper presented at the 13th Congress of the Latin American Studies Association Boston), October 23-25, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Patricia Wilson, A Comparative Evaluation of Regionalization and Decentralization in Nicaragua, (Working Paper Series No. 1, University of Texas, Austin), July 1986 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Michael Conroy, Internal Migration, War, and the Regional Outreach of the State: An Analysis of the Nicaraguan Public Sector, 1980-85 (Paper presented to the XIII LASA Congress, Boston), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Anna Lisa Peterson, Christian Base Communities in Revolutionary Nicaragua Programa de Estudios de Participation Popular Managua, Nicaragua, September 1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - The Elections in Nicaragua: November 1984: Report of the Irish Inter-Party Parliamentary Delegation (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Chitnis, Lord. The Election in Nicaragua, November 4, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Willy Brandt, et. al., Socialist International Report on the 1984 Election, November 7, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Thom Kerstiens and Piet Nelissen, Dutch Government Report on the 1984 Election, November 4, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Parliamentary Human Rights Group. A Report of the British Parliamentary Delegation to Nicaragua to Observe the Presidential and National Assembly Elections, November 4, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 38)